AKINPELU IFEOLUWA ENOCH

Port Harcourt, Nigeria

+2347042958528 🖂 Ifeoluwaakinpelu05@gmail.com in LinkedIn Profile My Portfolio

Profile Summary

An aspiring IT professional with 2 years of experience in Python Development, AI Engineering, and IT Project Management with a strong background in Computing Science. I specialize in creating smart solutions, leading successful IT projects, and using technology to solve real human problems. I have worked on developing some AI tools leveraging LLM models, managing small to mid-level IT projects, and turning complex ideas into clear, practical plans that meet business goals on time and within budget. I look forward to managing diverse software/hardware projects involving Artificial Intelligence (AI) integration.

Skills Developed Thus Far

Soft skills: Critical Thinking, Adaptability, Problem Solving, Leadership, Resilience.

Functional Skills: Effective Communication, Team Leadership, Project Prioritization, Project Planning, Process Improvement, Requirement Gathering, Agile & Waterfall Project Execution Methodologies.

Technical skills: Python, Flask, Django, Git, GitHub, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Generative AI, API Documentation, Jira, Click up, Monday.com, Asana, Trello, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

Professional Experience

Kingdom Portal Network, United Kingdom - Remote

Nov 2024 - Present

Role: Technical Project Manager

Responsibilities:

- Defined and executed project scope, goals, and deliverables, aligning with business objectives and ensuring a 98% alignment with stakeholder expectations.
- Develop detailed project plans, schedules, and budgets while monitoring progress and mitigating risks.
- Led 3 technical team and oversee end-to-end project lifecycle, from initiation to deployment, ensuring quality and efficiency.
- Communicated project status and risks to stakeholders, providing bi-weekly reports and ensuring 100% transparency in all project phases.
- Optimized project workflows by implementing Jira and Confluence, reducing task completion time by 18% across the team.

Stormcell Technology, Port Harcourt - Remote

Contract

Role: Software Project Manager

Responsibilities:

- Worked with stakeholders to define clear and detailed project requirements before development began, ensuring alignment with business objectives.
- Developed structured project plans, including timelines, milestones, resource allocation, and risk assessment, to guide the sequential phases of software development.
- Led the successful deployment of 3 software products, managing the end-to-end development lifecycle from planning to release.
- Coordinated cross-functional teams, including developers, designer, and QA tester, ensuring timely project completion and delivery.
- Provided structured post-launch support, collecting feedback and coordinating necessary updates while ensuring software stability.

Pan African Institute, Port Harcourt – NYSC (On-site)

Jan 2024 – Oct 2024

Role: Technical Officer

Responsibilities:

- Managed IT infrastructure and provided technical support, ensuring 99% system uptime for staff and learners.
- Maintained software solutions, improving operational efficiency by 20%.
- Conducted technical training sessions for staff, learners on digital literacy and effective system usage.
- Trained learners in Data Analysis, Computer Appreciation, and Python Programming, enhancing their technical skills and employability.

Education

Osun State University, Osogbo, Nigeria

Dec 2019 – Aug 2023

B.Sc. Computer Science Second Class Upper Division

Certifications

•	Project Management Professional (PMP), PMI		In Progress
•	Forward Program, McKinsey & Company	2024	View Credentials
•	Project Management Certification, Google	2024	View Credentials
•	Generative AI for Project Managers, PMI	2024	View Credentials
•	Kickoff – Agile Project Management, PMI	2024	View Credentials